National Coalition to Abolish the Death Penalty; Records apap298
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Video, 1985-2005; 8; 5.40 cubic ft.
  - Juveniles, Undated (Vhs 105)
  - Les Couloirs de la Mort (The Colors of Death): A French documentary about the death penalty, 1996 November 16 (Vhs 106)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience: 10 tapes - The Lighting the Torch of Conscience Movement involves organizing of religious leaders to campaign against the death penalty, Undated (Vhs 107)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 108)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 109)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 110)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 111)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 112)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 113)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 114)
  - Lighting the Torch of Conscience, Undated (Vhs 115)
  - Major Gift Solicitation: Kim Klein gives advice on how to solicit major gifts, Undated (Vhs 116)
  - Making Peace: A Moria Productions Series for The Independent Television Service, Undated (Vhs 117)
  - Making Society Safe: The Execution of Scum - SAD (Students Avocation Death) in Northern California explain the pros of the death penalty any why it should be used more often, Undated (Vhs 118)
  - Media Coverage of the John Wayne Gacy Execution: Several media stations covert he John Wayne Gacy execution, 1994 May (Vhs 119)
  - Arthur Miller Headlines on Trial: Should Juveniles Get the Death Penalty? - Victor Streib, Donna Hameperian, Daniel Popeo, and the Indiana State Prosecutor discuss whether it is morally right to send juveniles to death row, 1987 February 14 (Vhs 120)
  - Ramon Montoya Excerpt: Excerpt of Montoya's body being received by thousands at Hidalgo, Texas, 1993 March 26-28 (Vhs 121)
  - MSN-NBC "Death Penalty": Steven Hawkins is interviewed concerning the release of John Payne off of death row and the actions of Governor Allen, 1996 November 9 (Vhs 122)
  - My Piece of Sky: A first hand look at death row from an inmate's point of view, Undated (Vhs 123)
  - NBC Nightly News - Shareef Cousin, 1997 December 2 (Vhs 124)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Coverage of the NCADP Annual Conference in New Orleans, Louisiana at Loyola University, 1986 (Vhs 125)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Footage from the NCADP Annual Conference in New Orleans, Louisiana at Loyola University, 1986 (Vhs 126)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Coverage of the NCADP Annual Conference, 1987 November 14 (Vhs 127)
  - NCADP Annual Conference - Bad Lawyering Workshop, Awards, Reception, 1987 November 15 (Vhs 128)
  - NCADP Annual Conference - Opening: Footage of the opening ceremonies of the 1995 Annual Conference (Vhs 129)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Keynote Address by Ms. Mo-Janku Gumbi, South Africa & Awards Ceremony, 1995 August 5 (Vhs 130)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Saturday Evening Banquet, 1995 August 5 (Vhs 131)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: 1995 Meeting Audio Only, 1995 August 5 (Vhs 132)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: KTVI-TV Channel 2 News at 6:03pm, 1998 October 2 (Vhs 133)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Coverage of the annual conference in St. Louis, Missouri, 1999 (Vhs 134)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: 1999 Conference in Philadelphia (Vhs 135)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Raleigh, North Carolina Tape 1, 2001 (Vhs 136)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Raleigh, North Carolina Tape 2, 2001 (Vhs 137)
  - NCADP Annual Conference: Raleigh, North Carolina Tape 3, 2001 (Vhs 138)
  - News - Joseph O'Dell, Death Row Press Conference, Richmond, Virginia, 1996 July 24 (Vhs 139)
  - News Coverage: Interview with Kevin Stanford, a death row inmate, and Stephen Bright, 1998 March (Vhs 140)
  - Nightline - Ted Bundy, 1989 January 23 (Vhs 141)
  - Nightline - Mario Marquez execution, 1995 January 16-17 (Vhs 142)
  - Nightline - Payne v. Tennessee, hanging and the death penalty, 1990 April 3 (Vhs 143)
  - Off Center Productions, "A Pattern of Exclusion, The Trial of Thomas Miller-El" 13:30, 2002 February 4 (Vhs 144)
  - One Life on the Edge - Jamie Elizalde, Jr. 26:00, 2005 October 8 (Dvd 4)
  - One More Voice, produced and directed by Stephanie Gibson & Meg Heisse, 1998 (Vhs 145)
  - "Paradise Lost" A special about 3 juveniles accused of killing 3 small boys, 1996 (Vhs 146)
  - Peek v. State, 1985 October 7 (Vhs 147)
  - Pittsburgh's Talking "Death Penalty": Sam Sheppard, Jr. of Murder Victims Families for Reconciliation discusses the organization and the case of his father, Sam Sheppard, 1990 June 8 (Vhs 148)
  - Playwrite Express - '94: A play about a politician trying to become governor and his struggle to say he believes in the death penalty for votes when he actually he is an opponent, Undated (Vhs 149)
  - Politics and the Death Penalty: The question of whether rational discourse and due process can survive in the American political arena is examined, 1993 August 9 (Vhs 150)
  - Sister Helen Prejean, Undated (Vhs 151)
  - Sister Helen Prejean speaking: Sister Helen Prejean speaks about her award winning book Dead Man Walking and shares her experiences as a spiritual advisor to many death row inmates, Undated (Vhs 152)
  - Racism and the Death Penalty: DPIC-Chattahoochee Report - ABC World News, Fox Morning News and the CNN World Report on racism and the death penalty, 1991 July 10-20 (Vhs 153)
  - Reasonable Doubt: The case of Joe Giarratano, 1990 (Vhs 154)
  - The Religious Community Confronts Death Penalty: This film discusses issues such as cost, revenge, deterrence, and racism 25:24, Undated (Vhs 155)
  - Reunion of Law Clerks and Research Associates of Judge A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr. at Harvard University and the Judge's home - Part 1, 1998 May 2-3 (Vhs 156)
  - Reunion of Law Clerks and Research Associates of Judge A. Leon Higginbotham, Jr. at Harvard University and the Judge's home - Part 2, 1998 May 2-3 (Vhs 157)
  - Rights for All-Amnesty International's Campaign on the USA, 1999 (Vhs 158)
  - Rivera Live - On Capital Punishment: CNBC Geraldo Rivera discusses the death penalty, 1994 May 9 (Vhs 159)
  - Darlie Router on Maury Povich, 1997 May 19 (Vhs 160)
  - Should the Death Penalty be Abolished? Great Debate, 2002 November (Vhs 161)
  - Slideshow medly showing public action, Undated (Vhs 162)
  - Socialist Scholars Conference CUNY/NYC: Panel #72 Back on Death Row: A Reassessment of Capital Punishment in America with Bianca Jagger, Steven Bright, Kevin Doyle, 1999 April 11 (Vhs 163)
  - Somebody Has to Shoot the Picture (HBO), 1990 (Vhs 164)
  - Somebody Has to Shoot the Picture: HBO presents a film about an inmate who wishes to have still pictures of his execution taken, 1990 (Vhs 165)
  - Southern Poverty Law Center: Historical View of the SPLC and what the organization hopes to move to, Undated (Vhs 166)
  - Stafford Smith Program, Undated (Vhs 167)
  - Stones: The Death Penalty Art Show, 2001 (Vhs 168)
  - Texas Moratorium: Balancing The Scales 30 minute version, Undated (Vhs 169)
  - Texas Moratorium: Balancing The Scales 30 minute version, Undated (Vhs 170)
  - Thou Shall Not Kill, Undated (Vhs 171)
  - Thou Shall Not Kill: A biblical show that goes through scriptures of the bible to show that God forbids capital punishment, Undated (Vhs 172)
  - Too Flawed To Fix: The Illinois Death Penalty Experience, Peace Productions, Undated (Vhs 173)
  - Trial Story: Florida v. Ferrell, The Vampire Murderer, Court-TV, Undated (Vhs 174)
  - Tribute to Former Supreme Court Justice William Brennan: This video celebrates the work of anti-death penalty Supreme Court Justice William Brennan, 1994 November 10 (Vhs 175)
  - University of Maryland Eastern Shore Panel on Capital Punishment, 1997 April 9 (Vhs 176)
  - Various Interviews: Report on David Lawson and televised executions, ABC News a deep look at the case of Joe Burrows and his innocence, Report on lethal injections, Undated (Vhs 177)
  - Various News Coverage: ABC World News Tonight :To Live or Die", CBS 60 Minutes "Death Wish", ABC World News Sunday "Cost of the Death Penalty, Undated (Vhs 178)
  - Various News Shows: 20/20: Murderers fleeing to Abolitionist Countries, Eye on America: Battered Women who kill their partners, Niteline: Tennessee v. Payne, Undated (Vhs 179)
  - Various Programs: Fox Morning News, ABC World News Tonight, CNN Cable Network, News Channel 8, Undated (Vhs 180)
  - Victims families' & friends - "Don't Kill Me" Journey of Hop featuring Sister Helen Prejean, Undated (Vhs 181)
  - Virginia Currents: Host Rodger Coleman talks about current issues in Virginia, Undated (Vhs 182)
  - Voice of Democracy: Criminal Justice - Documentary on the news media effect on the publics view of crime, Undated (Vhs 183)
  - Who Killed Vincent Chin?, Undated (Vhs 184)
  - Whither Civil Rights, 35 Years After the Murder of Chaney, Schwerner and Goodman? - Committee on Civil Rights, Ronald J. Tabak (Program Moderator), Undated (Vhs 185)
  - Witches of Eastwick, Othello, The Charlie Rose Show: Ben Jealous talks about his 1997 Rhodes Scholar Award, Undated (Vhs 186)
  - Witness, Mark Landsman: Boods Not Bars, :30 second PSA, 3 minute PSA, 2000 (Vhs 187)
  - Witness to the Execution: HBO presents a fictional movie about a televised execution, Undated (Vhs 188)
  - Working Films - Capital Punishment, Undated (Dvd 5)
  - Wrongly Convicted - How the Innocent are Sent to Death Row. A Definitive Symposium, Professor Michael Radelet, University of Florida, 1999 September 16 (Vhs 189)
  - Unlabeled VHS tape, Undated (Vhs 190)